Hello, everyone.
大家好。
So today we are going to talk about demand beijing and before starting
今天我们要讨论需求北京，在开始之前
thanks a lot,
非常感谢。
everyone for filling in the survey about the class great feedback.
感谢大家填写关于课程的调查问卷，提供了很好的反馈。
And we are going to try to act on it.
我们将尝试采取行动。
Before let me start with the same figure,
在让我开始之前，让我先解释一下相同的图表。
which I think you went over last lecture.
我认为这是你在上一堂课上讲过的内容。
But let me do it again,
但是让我再试一次，
because it's a very important figure,
因为这是一个非常重要的数字，
because with everything together,
因为一切都在一起，
all the memory related concepts,
所有与内存相关的概念
we have learned so far.
我们目前已经学到了。
As always, if you have any questions,
如常，如果你有任何问题，
please do not hesitate to,
请不要犹豫，
let me know.
请告诉我。
So here we have the virtual address on the left.
这里我们左边是虚拟地址。
And you remember the virtual address is what the programs and what
你记得虚拟地址是程序和操作系统使用的地址吗？
the processor sees.
处理器所看到的。
On the right hand side,
在右侧
you have the physical,
你拥有物理资源，
the memory address.
内存地址。
What we learn, we learn,
我们所学的，我们就学到了。
we learn about the address translation in which these virtual addresses
我们学习了地址转换，其中包括虚拟地址。
are translated to physical addresses.
被翻译成物理地址。
And one way we did that is through page multi level page.
我们通过多级页表的方式来实现这一点。
In this example, we are showing two level beijing.
在这个例子中，我们展示了两层的北京。
And therefore the virtual address have consist of three fields.
因此，虚拟地址由三个字段组成。
The last one,
最后一个，
the blue is blue in this figure is the offset.
这个图中的蓝色是偏移量。
The offset, the beating,
偏移量，跳动，
the offset remains unchanged in the physical address.
偏移量在物理地址中保持不变。
Then the first field of the visual address,
然后是视觉地址的第一个字段，
it's an index to the first level in the first level bay stable.
这是指向第一层的索引，位于第一层货架稳定区。
And at that address, in the first day,
在那个地址上，第一天，
at that location in the first page table,
在第一个页表的那个位置上，
you find the address of another page table at the second level.
你在第二级找到了另一个页表的地址。
The second field in the address of ritual between index denoted here.
这里所指的地址中的第二个字段是索引之间的仪式。
It's an index to the second level page table,
这是指向二级页表的索引。
which is referenced from the first label level page label.
这是从第一个标签级别页面标签引用的。
At the corresponding location in the second level page table.
在二级页表中相应的位置。
You have the physical page number.
你有物理页号。
And now your concatenate is a physical page number with the offset.
现在你的连接操作是将物理页号与偏移量拼接在一起。
You got the physical others is the physical page number,
你得到的是物理地址，而其他的是物理页号。
as you see here,
正如你在这里看到的，
the big did.
大事发生了。
And the offset represent the offset within that page.
偏移量表示在该页内的偏移位置。
So this is virtual address,
这是虚拟地址。
the address translation from virtual addresses to physical addresses using
使用虚拟地址到物理地址的地址转换
two level pages.
两级页表。
In addition, what you also learn about is about translation.
此外，你还会学习关于翻译的内容。
Look aside buffers.
旁路缓冲区
Can someone tell me why do we need a translation?
有人可以告诉我为什么我们需要翻译吗？
Look aside buffer or tlb for sure?
是选择旁路缓冲器还是转译后备缓冲器？
What problem does it solve?
它解决了什么问题？
It's exact.
没问题。
Thanks, allison and gilbert.
谢谢，Allison和Gilbert。
You are correct.
你是正确的。
So fundamentally,
从根本上说，
as you see,
正如你所看到的，
with the page two level page tables,
使用两级页表
you need in order to do the translation,
为了进行翻译，您需要
you need to do multiple memory access is we need to get a location
你需要进行多次内存访问是因为我们需要获取一个位置。
from the first page,
从第一页开始，
from the first level page table,
从一级页表开始，
then to access the second level page table,
然后访问第二级页表。
a bunch, this means a bunch of memory access is,
一大堆，这意味着大量的内存访问。
right.
好的。
When you are going to look to a physical,
当你要进行体检时，
to try to just look a location in memory,
尝试仅查看内存中的一个位置
to fetch an instruction or to access data,
获取指令或访问数据，
you have to do multiple memory axis, which is very slow.
你需要执行多次内存访问，这会非常慢。
So translation look aside buffer, solve this problem.
翻译查找缓冲区，解决这个问题。
So it's a small table,
所以这是一个小表格，
which takes a virtual address that takes the first two fields
该函数接受一个虚拟地址，其中包含了前两个字段。
in the virtual address,
在虚拟地址中，
which contains a page information and maps that to the physical page number.
其中包含页面信息，并将其映射到物理页面编号。
And this is happening.
而且这正在发生。
It's in harder.
这更难一些。
So the translation is very quick.
翻译非常迅速。
This still be in the processor.
这仍然在处理器中。
Then what is the other way we are going try to improve the performance?
那么我们还打算尝试哪种方式来提高性能呢？
Because even if we make one access to the ramp to the memory,
因为即使我们只对内存中的斜坡进行一次访问，
that the time to make that access a latency is much larger than accessing,
访问时间使得访问延迟比访问本身要大得多。
say,
说,
registers or in the processor.
寄存器或处理器中的寄存器。
Its order of mind,
它的思维方式，
you slower to access physical memory.
你访问物理内存的速度较慢。
To solve this problem,
要解决这个问题，
what you learned last lecture, we can.
上节课我们学到了什么，我们可以。
And also at 61 c earlier on,
之前也在61摄氏度。
it's about you are using cash,
这是关于您使用现金的事情。
right?
对的？
A cash.
现金。
So cash, it's a smaller memory.
所以缓存，它是一个较小的内存。
And because it's smaller,
而且因为它更小，
it can be either closer,
它可以是更接近的，
or it can be directly on the chip, on the processor.
或者它可以直接在芯片上，即处理器上。
Therefore,
因此，
the latency to access this cache is much lower than the latency to access
访问该缓存的延迟远低于访问的延迟。
the physical memory.
物理内存。
If the data you are looking for,
如果你要查找的数据，
it's already in cash,
已经是现金了
the access will be much quicker.
访问速度将会更快。
And here we show set associative cache.
这里我们展示了集合关联缓存。
You remember that the set associative cache,
你记得集合关联缓存，
you have multiple sets of this kind of multiple
你有多个这种类型的多个集合。
sets of of blocks.
一组块。
And each of them is identified by a tag with any set you
每个集合中的每个元素都由一个标签进行标识。
can associate with me,
可以与我联系吗？
identify.
识别。
One of this is here is represented by a line.
这里的一个代表通过一条线表示。
One of these arose.
其中之一出现了。
How do you do that?
你是如何做到的？
So now,
所以现在，
the cash is addressed with a physical address.
现金使用物理地址进行标识。
So the physical address now is divided into other three fields,
所以现在物理地址被分成了另外三个字段，
which is very tag index and byte.
这是非常标签索引和字节。
And the index.
还有索引。
If you have a memory set associated as set associated cash,
如果你有一个与缓存关联的内存集合，
the index points to a particular set of such rows.
索引指向一组特定的行。
And then the tag is going to identify a row in the set.
然后标签将用于标识集合中的一行。
And finally,
最后，
or in a bite,
简而言之，
will specify an index of the byte you are looking for in that row.
将在该行中指定要查找的字节的索引。
We also refer it as a block to these cells.
我们也将这些单元格称为块。
This is it.
就是这样了。
You have address translation to speed up the address translation.
你可以使用地址转换来加速地址转换过程。
You use atlb which maps in hardware,
你使用的是硬件映射的ATLB。
the virtual pace number to
虚拟页号
the physical pace number.
物理页码编号。
And then to farther speed up the access to the memory,
为了进一步加快对内存的访问速度，
we use a cache and to locate the data in the cache,
我们使用缓存来定位缓存中的数据。
we use these three fields,
我们使用这三个字段，
tag index and buy.
标签索引和购买。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Just remember that the tlb you address atlb with a virtual page number,
请记住，TLB是通过虚拟页号来寻址的。
and you address a cache with a physical address.
你使用物理地址来访问缓存。
So now,
所以现在，
the one question,
一个问题，
if you remember,
如果你记得的话，
is there is a virtual address space can be larger than the physical address.
虚拟地址空间可以比物理地址空间更大吗？
Also,
另外，
you have multiple virtual address spaces which are going to multiplex
你有多个虚拟地址空间，它们将进行多路复用。
the same physical others,
相同的物理特征，其他方面不同。
because each process has its own virtual address space.
因为每个进程都有自己的虚拟地址空间。
This means that at a given time,
这意味着在某个特定的时间，
you may not be able to store all the virtual address,
你可能无法存储所有的虚拟地址。
all the data in the virtual address space,
虚拟地址空间中的所有数据，
across all process processes,
在所有进程中，
in the physical memory.
在物理内存中。
And if you cannot do that,
如果你不能做到的话，
some of these pages,
其中一些页面，
you need to put somewhere else.
你需要把它放在别的地方。
Typically, somewhere else is on the disk or ssd now,
通常，现在的数据通常存储在磁盘或固态硬盘上。
the question is about when you need a page,
这个问题是关于何时需要一个页面的。
which is not in the memory, it's on the disk.
这个数据不在内存中，而是在磁盘上。
How do you go about getting that page in memory?
你如何将那个页面加载到内存中？
That's what we are going to learn and focus on is the remaining of this lecture.
我们将在本讲座的剩余部分学习和关注的就是这个。
And when we are going to access a page,
当我们要访问一个页面时，
which is not in physical memory,
不在物理内存中的
what it called, you, it,
你叫什么名字？你是什么东西？
then what happens?
然后会发生什么？
You have a page four.
你有一页是第四页。
And the way this is indicated,
这是通过以下方式表示的，
remember that when you do the batteries translation,
请记住，在进行电池翻译时，
you look in the page table, in the page table,
你查看页表，在页表中，
you find a page table entry corresponding to that page.
你找到了与该页面对应的页表项。
So that page table entry has a bit,
所以这个页表项有一个位，
which is saying, for instance,
例如，这句话是说，
it's invalid bit.
这是无效位。
And if that be dissect,
如果要进行解剖的话，
this means that the page is not present in the physical memory.
这意味着页面不在物理内存中。
Okay?
好的？
Now a baseball will occur.
现在将进行一场棒球比赛。
And what happens?
发生了什么事情？
So on baseball,
关于棒球，
you have to engage the operating system,
你需要调用操作系统。
and the operating system will make sure to bring the right page
操作系统将确保将正确的页面调入内存
from the disk to memory.
从磁盘到内存。
So then you are going to be able to continue the execution of the program
那么你将能够继续执行程序。
to bring a page from the disk to the physical memory.
将页面从磁盘调入物理内存。
You need to find a place to put it.
你需要找一个地方放它。
If you have free space,
如果你有空闲空间，
you bring it down.
你把它放下来。
If you don't have free space,
如果你没有空闲空间，
they need to take an existing page and replace it with a new page.
他们需要将现有的页面替换为新页面。
You want to bring in memory.
你想将其加载到内存中。
Now, if that page you want to replace has been written,
现在，如果你想要替换的页面已经被编写完成，
has been modified,
已经被修改了。
then you need to put it on the disk,
那么你需要将它存储到磁盘上。
save it on the disk.
将其保存在磁盘上。
Before you replace it is on your page.
在你替换之前，它在你的页面上。
That's what it is.
就是这样。
We are going to go through this process several times during this lecture,
在本次讲座中，我们将多次进行这个过程。
to make sure that the concepts are clear.
为了确保概念清晰。
And before going forward,
在继续之前，
notice that a it's a fundamental inversion here that you have the hardware.
请注意，这里存在一个基本的颠倒，即硬件是你拥有的。
It causes a page fault in this case,
在这种情况下会引发页面错误。
because the invalid bit or in the page table entry set,
因为页表项中设置了无效位或无效标志位，
which then this fall is treated in software,
然后在本学期中，这将在软件中进行处理。
right?
对的？
As opposed to interrupts where the interacts are treated in hardware.
与中断不同，交互是在硬件中处理的。
And then once you select the handle of the internet, only,
然后一旦你选择了互联网的句柄，只有这个，
then you go into software.
然后你进入软件领域。
Again, to put things into perspective.
再次，为了让事情更清晰明了。
Right now,
现在，
this is you have different levels of memory or storage.
这是指计算机系统中存在不同层次的内存或存储器。
You have our own cheap cash.
你有自己的廉价现金。
Here is a processor.
这是一个处理器。
And in today's processors,
在当今的处理器中，
you actually have multiple cash cashes level of cash is even known
你实际上有多个现金缓存层级，甚至有些现金层级是已知的。
as single processor,
作为单处理器，
because you may have a cache for each core.
因为每个核心可能都有自己的缓存。
And then you may have a unified cache,
然后你可以拥有一个统一的缓存。
which is across all course.
这适用于所有课程。
Then you have second level cache.
然后你有第二级缓存。
It's a main memory.
这是主内存。
Then is this like secondary storage?
这是否类似于辅助存储？
Of course,
当然可以。
you can even have tertiary storage tape or some kind of storage in the cloud.
你甚至可以拥有三级存储磁带或云存储。
What is the key here?
这里的关键是什么？
You like?
你喜欢吗？
What we are trying to do is catching with everything else.
我们正在努力赶上其他一切。
We're trying to do something very simple.
我们正在尝试做一些非常简单的事情。
We want to try to have the cake and eat it too.
我们想要尽量两全其美。
So we want to have,
所以我们想要有，
we want to build a system which behaves like it has a storage of the largest
我们想要构建一个系统，它的行为就像拥有最大存储空间一样。
storage device.
存储设备。
It has access to,
它具有访问权限，
but the latency to access that storage.
但是访问该存储的延迟。
It's the same as accessing zone, cheap cash.
这与访问区域和廉价现金相同。
That's a holy great.
太棒了！
Right?
对吗？
And again,
再次，
at the key here is that at every level,
关键在于，在每个层次上，
the key technique is a cash is using cash.
关键技术是使用现金。
You catch the data from the next level,
你从下一层捕获数据，
and you hope that for the mass,
你希望对于大众来说，
most of the vast majority of time,
大部分时间，绝大多数时间，
the program will only use the data in that cache.
该程序只会使用缓存中的数据。
You don't go to the next level.
你没有进入下一关。
And if the program exhibit locality,
如果程序表现出局部性，
therefore,
因此，
he spends most of the time in a reasonably small portion of the code
他在代码的一个相对较小的部分花费了大部分的时间
or touching small portion of the data.
或者只是触及数据的一小部分。
You are in luck,
你很幸运，
because as long as you put this heavily accessed a region of memory
因为只要你将这个频繁访问的内存区域放置在
of a program in the cache,
在缓存中的程序
you are fine.
你很好。
And the last point to make here,
最后一个要提到的点是，
the way to think about the main memory,
关于主存储器的思考方式
it as a cash for the secondary storage, for the disk.
它作为二级存储器的现金，用于磁盘。
But it's, again, at each level,
但是，再次强调，在每个层次上，
you can think it's a cache for the next level.
你可以把它看作是下一级的缓存。
But we don't call it cash,
但是我们不称之为现金，
we call it paging.
我们称之为分页。
So here is, again,
这里是，再次，
another figure showing user baseball to what I described earlier.
另一个图示展示了我之前描述的用户棒球情况。
In words,
用文字来描述的话，
this is using some animation to drive the point how so have say you have
这里使用一些动画来强调一下，你要说的是你有什么要说的。
an instruction and you do the instruction fetch,
一条指令，然后你进行指令获取操作。
then you go to the memory management,
然后你进入了内存管理。
you need the memory management,
你需要内存管理。
you need to handle the base table,
你需要处理基本表。
tlb and all of these great stuff to do address translation.
TLB（Translation Lookaside Buffer）和其他一些伟大的东西用于地址转换。
Now, you go,
现在，你可以开始了。
you find the page table entry.
你找到了页表项。
And then from the patient, the entries,
然后从患者那里获取条目，
we are going to have the page number and the offset.
我们将会有页号和偏移量。
The offset keep coming from the virtual address.
偏移量来自虚拟地址。
The page number comes after translation.
翻译后的页码会出现在之后。
But now let's assume that you do when you execute the next instruction,
但是现在假设当你执行下一条指令时，
you go to the page table,
你需要访问页表。
but the entry doesn't exist or it existed by and it's invalid.
但该条目不存在，或者它曾经存在但已失效。
So then you have a page fault.
那么你遇到了一个页面错误。
You go to the operating system to take care of things.
你去操作系统处理事务。
The page table, as i'm sorry,
页表，很抱歉，
the operating system on fault,
操作系统出现故障，
is going to do what is going basically too loud to locate the page on the disk,
这句话的意思是：要做的事情基本上是太吵了，无法定位磁盘上的页面。
which is required by the program.
这是程序所需的。
Load that page in the physical memory,
将该页面加载到物理内存中。
and then update the page table entry.
然后更新页表项。
Finally, you restart the program,
最后，你重新启动程序。
and the program will retry the previous instruction,
程序将会重新尝试之前的指令，
which calls a page fault.
这会引发一个页错误。
Now,
现在，
the previous instruction is going to have the same look to do the same page
前一条指令将具有相同的外观来执行相同的页面。
from the same virtual address.
从相同的虚拟地址。
But now,
但是现在，
the page it's already in the memory,
该页面已经在内存中了。
so you are going to access that page and continue execution.
所以你将访问那个页面并继续执行。
Is that clear?
这清楚吗？
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
So now we just said that the main page beijing is like cash,
所以现在我们刚刚说过，北京的主要页面就像现金一样。
the memory act as a cash for the persistent storage like these courses or sst
内存充当持久存储（如这些课程或固态存储器）的缓存。
now let's look from the. of your the cashing as from the point of
现在让我们从你的缓存的角度来看。
view of a cash and characterize
现金的视角和特征描述
demand beijing.
需求：北京。
First of all, what is the block size?
首先，块大小是什么？
What is the cash granada?
"现金格拉纳达"是指一种现金奖励或补贴计划。这种计划通常由政府、组织或企业提供，旨在鼓励个人或团体在特定领域或项目中取得成就或达到目标。格拉纳达通常以现金形式提供，可以用于个人消费、投资或其他用途。
The block size?
块大小是多少？
It's basically, in this case, you,
在这种情况下，基本上是你，
as a joke.
作为一个笑话。
Now, it's 1 page,
现在，只有一页。
which is, say,
比如说，
four kilobytes between one kilobytes and 16 kilobytes.
一千六百字节和一千字节之间有四千字节。
Typically,
通常情况下，
what is the organization of the cash?
现金的组织结构是什么？
We learned about direct map cache,
我们学习了直接映射缓存。
fully associative set associated.
完全关联集关联。
The answer here is that it's fully associated provides you the most
这里的答案是完全关联提供给你最多的
is the most efficient in using the cash.
在使用现金方面最高效。
If you remember,
如果你还记得的话，
why Why is a fully associative memory,
为什么全关联存储器是全关联的？
the most effective in using the cash storage?
如何最有效地使用现金储存？
You can place it anywhere.
你可以把它放在任何地方。
There are no conflicts,
没有冲突。
there are no conflict misses.
没有冲突缺失。
Like you remember his direct map cash,
就像你记得他的直接映射缓存一样，
you have conflict misses.
你有冲突缺失。
You don't have conflict misses here with the associative cash.
在这里，使用关联缓存不会出现冲突缺失。
There is a question here.
这里有一个问题。
So the page fault we see in the error message happen on the demand,
所以我们在错误消息中看到的页面错误发生在需求方面。
beijing does not save the program.
北京不保存程序。
Maybe you can ask again the question.
也许你可以再问一遍问题。
I am afraid I do not understand whatever we are talking about here.
很抱歉，我不明白我们在这里讨论的是什么。
We are talking about the please ask the question again,
请再次提出问题，我们正在讨论。
and i'll be happy to answer.
我很乐意回答。
Now, how do you locate the page?
现在，你如何定位页面？
First to check the dlb then you do the page traversal if it's
首先检查dlb，然后进行页面遍历，如果是的话。
not in the tlb right?
不在TLB中吗？
Is how you locate the page.
这是你定位页面的方式。
What is the page replacement policy?
页面置换策略是什么？
As you'll see,
正如你所看到的，
it's we want allah you,
我们希望你全心全意地信仰真主。
at least recently used,
至少最近使用的
as there are others.
因为还有其他人。
We are going to look at other replacement policies,
我们将研究其他的替换策略，
but typically, we try to have an approximation of al rego.
但通常情况下，我们会尽量对所有寄存器进行近似。
We have to have an approximation of area,
我们需要一个面积的近似值。
because you just implementing area can be too expensive.
因为你只是在实现一个区域可能会太昂贵。
We learn about that.
我们已经了解了这个。
What happened on a miss?
在缺失时发生了什么？
You saw that.
你看到了。
Right?
对吗？
When there is a miss,
当发生缺失时，
you are going to find the page on the disk and bring the page in the memory.
你需要在磁盘上找到页面并将页面调入内存。
What happens on the right?
右边发生了什么？
Remember that the cache is a copy of the data from memory.
请记住，缓存是从内存中复制的数据。
If you modify the data in the cache,
如果你修改了缓存中的数据，
you need also to modify as the copy of that data in memory.
你还需要修改内存中的数据副本。
And there are two ways to modify it.
并且有两种方法可以进行修改。
One is right through.
一个是正确的。
This means that as soon as you update the cash,
这意味着一旦你更新现金，
also you update the main memory.
你还需要更新主存储器。
The second method is right back.
第二种方法是右转回来。
You just update the cash when you really want to replace the data
当你真正想要替换数据时，只需更新现金即可。
in the cache with some other data from to bring it in,
将其与其他数据一起放入缓存中，以便将其带入缓存中。
then you are going to write the data from the cache to the
然后你将把数据从缓存写入
memory before replacing it.
在替换之前的内存。
In this case, we are talking about memory and the disk.
在这种情况下，我们正在讨论内存和磁盘。
We are definitely talking about right back.
我们确实在谈论右后卫。
Why did I arrive back in this case?
为什么我又回到了这个情况下？
Tell me why don't we do right through?
告诉我为什么我们不能一直做正确的事情？
Excellent.
非常好。
So allison and tyro.
所以是艾莉森和泰罗。
So this is because it's very expensive to read the data from the disk.
这是因为从磁盘读取数据非常昂贵。
It can be order of magnitude more expensive.
它可能会贵上一个数量级。
Just to give you a sense,
只是为了让你有个概念，
the latency to memory
内存延迟
is maybe between 15 nanoseconds and 100 nanoseconds.
可能在15纳秒到100纳秒之间。
The latency to read and write from a disk can be 1 million seconds.
从磁盘读取和写入的延迟可以达到100万秒。
What is 34, or that are minded?
34是一个数字，表示三十四。"that are minded"这个短语的意思是"有意愿"或"有意识"。
So it's huge difference.
所以这是一个巨大的差异。
So that's how you avoid.
这就是你避免的方法。
You try to minimize the number of times you write data back to the storage
你尽量减少将数据写回存储的次数。
to the risk.
面临风险。
I see, so this is a question.
我明白了，所以这是一个问题。
It seems like when the baseball happens for the first time,
似乎是当棒球首次出现时，
it tries a program again after the man paging instead of killing
在内存分页之后，它会尝试重新运行程序，而不是终止它。
the program right away.
立即运行该程序。
But on in zimbabwe often see page fold message,
但在津巴布韦经常会看到页面折叠的消息。
the painful message you are seeing when you are debugging is different.
当你在调试时看到的痛苦信息是不同的。
That is, for instance,
例如，
when you are going to try to access some invalid region in the memory,
当你尝试访问内存中的无效区域时，
like something you didn't allocate,
像你没有分配的东西一样，
for instance,
例如，
then you have faithful that is like you just have an address which
然后你有一个忠实的对象，就像你只有一个地址一样。
doesn't belong to and to read or write to another address,
不属于并且不能读取或写入另一个地址。
which doesn't belong to the program,
哪个不属于程序。
because it's not allocated yet.
因为它尚未分配。
So that's different.
所以这是不同的。
The special fault I was talking about is not visible to the program.
我所说的特殊故障对程序来说是不可见的。
This happens under the hood.
这是在幕后发生的。
And what you said is correct.
你说的是正确的。
That is on this page fault happens.
这是发生页面错误的地方。
Yes, you are going to do a trap,
是的，你要执行一个陷阱操作。
an exception trap to the operating system,
操作系统的异常陷阱
the operating system,
操作系统
get the page from the disk,
从磁盘获取页面
put in the memory.
存入内存。
And then you retry it and you restart the program from the same instruction.
然后你重试它，并从相同的指令重新启动程序。
But remember,
但是请记住，
we want to provide with the virtual memory,
我们希望提供虚拟内存。
the illusion of infinite physical memory.
无限物理内存的错觉。
This is one example.
这是一个例子。
Virtual memory is huge, is for your byte,
虚拟内存非常庞大，以字节为单位计算。
you have 32 bits addresses.
你有32位地址。
But now most of the machines,
但是现在大多数的机器，
even including your phone, has 64 bits.
即使包括你的手机在内，也只有64位。
So it's a huge amount of memory of virtual memory.
所以这是一个巨大的虚拟内存的数量。
There is no way you can have a physical memory,
你无法拥有物理内存。
large enough of all the entire visual memory of an application.
足够大以容纳应用程序的全部可视内存。
Then you map this kind of pages from the visual memory using the page table
然后你使用页表将这种页面从虚拟内存映射到物理内存。
to the physical memory.
到物理内存。
Then some of the page are,
然后一些页面是，
which are the not fitting the physical memory are going to be on the disk.
无法适应物理内存的部分将被存储在磁盘上。
Why is that?
为什么这样做呢？
Because the disk is much higher,
因为磁盘的速度要快得多，
even sst is much harder than a physical memory.
即使是单一系统图（SST），也比物理内存要困难得多。
You have a lot of more space.
你还有很多空间。
It's, again, going to the disk and getting the pace.
再次，它会访问磁盘并获取数据。
So demand beijing happen,
所以需求发生在北京。
transparent is not visible to the application.
透明对应用程序不可见。
The only way the application may notice is that it's a little bit slower,
应用程序唯一可能注意到的是它变得稍微慢一些，
because you need, instead of getting the data directly from memory,
因为你需要的是从内存中直接获取数据，而不是其他方式获取数据。
you have to go first the disk,
你必须先去磁盘。
move the data into memory, and then get the data.
将数据移入内存，然后获取数据。
This is a page table entry.
这是一个页表项。
If you remember, from two lectures ago,
如果你还记得，两节课之前的内容，
you have the page frame number,
你有页面帧号码。
the first 32 beats addresses address,
前32个位地址地址
the first page, the page frame number.
第一页，页面帧编号。
This represent the surface20 bits.
这表示了20位的表面。
The last 12, 20 bits,
最后的12个、20位。
12 bits are some a bunch of bits of
12位是一串位(bit)的集合。
each bit has a different semantics.
每个位都有不同的语义。
And for the purpose of this lecture,
为了本次讲座的目的，
we care about 2 bits.
我们关心的是2个比特。
One is p which is called present or valid.
其中一个是p，被称为当前或有效。
This basically says that the corresponding page is in memory.
这基本上表示相应的页面已经在内存中。
If p is zero, the bit is zero,
如果p为零，则该位为零。
then the page is not in memory somewhere on the disk.
那么该页面不在磁盘上的某个位置上。
And d is a dirty bit.
而 d 是一个脏位。
And this says, as a patient has been modified recently,
这句话的意思是，由于最近对患者进行了修改，
this has been modified since it was brought in memory.
这个在被加载到内存中之后已经被修改过了。
For instance, for example,
例如，举个例子，比如说，
this means that why do you think,
这意味着你为什么这样认为？
how do you think you are going to use a dirty bit?
你认为如何使用脏位？
Why do we need it?
我们为什么需要它？
It's exactly is to determine it's if you need to write the page back,
这是确定是否需要将页面写回的准确方法。
if we have to replace that page,
如果我们必须替换那个页面，
because we no longer have room in the physical memory to bring a new page,
因为我们的物理内存已经没有足够的空间来加载新的页面了。
then if the page we want to replace has been modified,
那么如果我们要替换的页面已被修改，
we need first to write to the disk,
我们首先需要将数据写入磁盘。
not with the information.
没有相关信息。
That's great.
太好了。
This is a demand.
这是一个要求。
Paging mechanism is very simple.
分页机制非常简单。
Again, it's like repeating it.
再次，就像重复一样。
You look at the pde baseball entry of the page.
你看一下页面上的PDE棒球条目。
If the bit of the pd is valid than the means that the page in memories,
如果页面描述符（pd）的位有效，则意味着页面在内存中。
you go and access the data from the memory.
你去访问内存中的数据。
If it's not valid,
如果不合法，
then this means that the page is not in memory.
这意味着页面不在内存中。
It's on the disk.
它在磁盘上。
And when you do that,
当你这样做的时候，
you these results in a trap,
你把这些结果陷入了一个陷阱中，
it's a page fault.
这是一个页面错误。
And 1 page fault,
并且发生了1次页面错误。
you choose an old page to replace.
你选择了一个旧页面来替换。
If you don't have enough room in the memory.
如果内存空间不足。
If that old page has a dirty bit set,
如果那个旧页面的脏位被设置了，
this means that you have to write that page to the disk.
这意味着你需要将该页面写入磁盘。
Then once you are done with that,
完成后，
you also need to add to invalidate the pt entry for the page,
你还需要添加代码来使页表项失效。
because now you are going to remove from the you are going to remove it
因为现在你要将它移除。
from the memory.
从内存中。
And also you need to invalidate the tlb entry for that page.
还有，你需要使该页面的TLB条目无效化。
Once you are done with it,
完成后，
you are going to bring the new page from the disk to memory in place
你将要将磁盘上的新页面就地加载到内存中。
of the old page.
旧页面的一部分。
And once you bring the new page,
一旦你带来了新页面，
your update to the pdu of the new page.
您对新页面的PDU的更新。
And you are ready to go.
你已经准备好了。
And by the way,
顺便说一下，
when this happens and operating system is doing all this kind of work
当发生这种情况时，操作系统正在进行所有这些工作。
to bring the page from the disk to memory,
将页面从磁盘加载到内存中，
it's a lot of io and in the meantime,
这涉及到很多输入输出操作，同时，
you try to scandal and run other processes which are not blocked.
你试图扫描并运行其他未被阻塞的进程。
So at those origins of the beijing and the origin of the beijing is states
北京的起源可以追溯到古代的国家。
long time ago from 70s and in 70s.
很久以前，从70年代开始，到70年代结束。
It was a time before everyone has a personal computer and what you have a terminal.
这是在每个人都拥有个人电脑之前的时代，你只有一个终端。
It looks like a computer, but it's just a terminal.
它看起来像一台计算机，但实际上只是一个终端。
And they are connected to the computers.
它们与计算机相连接。
You have many people running their programs on the same computer.
你有很多人在同一台计算机上运行他们的程序。
And they are using the computer from these terminals.
他们正在使用这些终端上的计算机。
Now, because you have so many users,
现在，由于你有很多用户，
and the physical memory was quite small.
而且物理内存非常小。
Again, not all the users programs could fit in the memory.
同样，不是所有用户的程序都能够适应内存。
So now you need to do you need the ability to
所以现在你需要做的是你需要有能力
swap and to put some of these a pages of these pages,
交换并将其中一些页面放置在这些页面中。
which are not used often,
很少使用的。
or they haven't used for a while to put them on the disk.
或者他们已经有一段时间没有使用了，将它们存储到磁盘上。
Right?
对吗？
This is what happened early on.
这是早期发生的事情。
That's why you have paid.
这就是你付款的原因。
This is basically the model you have,
这基本上是你所拥有的模型。
we should we are going to have in mind,
我们应该记住的是，
and we are going to continue to discuss the image, pay,
我们将继续讨论镜像和薪资问题。
demand, paging for the rest of the lecture.
剩下的讲座将涉及到需求分页。
Now, what happens when the pieces with the personal computers?
现在，个人电脑的部件会发生什么情况呢？
Actually, it's personal computers.
实际上，这是个人电脑。
Initially.
最初的。
You don't have visual memory.
你没有视觉记忆。
You have one program only running a on a machine,
你只有一个程序在一台机器上运行。
and that program taking the entire physical memory.
并且该程序占用了整个物理内存。
However,
然而，
as personal computers became more and more sophisticated and you run
随着个人电脑变得越来越复杂，你运行的任务也越来越多。
multiple programs on the same computer,
同一台计算机上的多个程序
now you're still,
现在你还静止不动，
you are back in square one,
你又回到了原点，
because like we discussed several times,
因为正如我们多次讨论过的那样，
the aggregate memory required by all processes,
所有进程所需的总内存
all the application running at a given time exceeds the physical memory.
在给定的时间内，所有运行的应用程序超过了物理内存的容量。
Again, what is a solution here?
这里的解决方案是什么？
Individualize them as a memo, the memory.
将它们个性化为备忘录，即内存。
And you need to keep some of these memory of this application on the disk.
你需要将这个应用程序的一部分内存保存在磁盘上。
The memory, hopefully, which is not accessed very often,
希望不经常访问的内存
all these.
所有这些。
And now machines are connected to the cloud,
现在机器与云相连接，
all of your phones and laptops.
你的所有手机和笔记本电脑。
And you have the same situation in the the cloud.
在云端中，你也面临着同样的情况。
You have very powerful computers,
你们有非常强大的计算机。
and they run a lot of applications.
他们运行了很多应用程序。
And they also,
而且他们也，
obviously with virtual members.
显然是使用虚成员。
This is, again,
这是，再次，
if you look at one machine,
如果你只看一台机器，
if you do the ps program status,
如果你执行ps命令来查看程序的状态，
this is kind of what you get.
这差不多就是你得到的东西。
And here i'm just showing the memory in this particular case is pretty utilized.
在这里，我只是展示了在这种特定情况下内存被充分利用的情况。
I say that you have 13 gigabytes of memory.
我说你有13GB的内存。
It's used, and only 2.7 is not used.
它被使用了，只有2.7没有被使用。
So it's more than 80% it's used.
所以它的使用率超过80%。
And some of them is shared memory.
其中一些是共享内存。
Remember that different application can share memory.
请记住，不同的应用程序可以共享内存。
For instance, if they use the same libraries,
例如，如果他们使用相同的库文件，
they share the code of those libraries,
它们共享这些库的代码。
because it doesn't make sense to make a copy of the same code for each
因为为每个相同的代码制作副本是没有意义的。
of the application.
应用程序的一部分。
So there are many uses of ritual memory and demand beijing.
因此，仪式记忆和需求北京有许多用途。
I remember that in the virtual memory or one segment,
我记得在虚拟内存或一个段中，
you have is a stack.
你拥有的是一个栈。
The stack grows downwards from the high addresses to the lower addresses,
栈从高地址向低地址增长。
as you allocate and to push more data on the stack,
当你分配内存并将更多数据推入堆栈时，
you may have to extend the stack.
你可能需要扩展栈。
So this is how you are going to do it.
这就是你要做的方式。
If you are going to want to expand the stack,
如果你想要扩展栈的话，
then it's, again, what will happen?
那么，再次发生什么？
You have a page fault.
你发生了一个页面错误。
You are going to go to the operating system,
你将要学习操作系统。
and the operating system is going to increase the side of the stack,
操作系统将增加栈的大小。
ok and allocate more memory for the stack.
好的，为栈分配更多的内存。
Another way is process fork.
另一种方式是进程分叉（fork）。
We discuss about that.
我们讨论这个问题。
Here.
这里。
We are going to re discuss again.
我们将重新讨论。
When you do a fork,
当你执行fork操作时，
you remember that the child process has the same code as the same in science.
你记得子进程与父进程有相同的代码。
And it has the same resources as a parent process.
它拥有与父进程相同的资源。
But because you have the same code,
但是因为你们有相同的代码，
one simple solution will be your copies,
一个简单的解决方案是复制您的文件。
the entire code,
整个代码
and the data from the parent process to the child process before you
在将数据从父进程传递给子进程之前，
can start the child process.
可以启动子进程。
The problem is that it will take a lot of time.
问题在于这将会花费很多时间。
So instead, what you do here is that when you create the child process,
所以在这里，你所做的是在创建子进程时，
you create it immediately and you have it.to all the memory of the parent process.
你立即创建它，并将其拥有到父进程的所有内存中。
So they share the same memory.
所以它们共享同一块内存。
The only difference is that from the point of view of the child process,
唯一的区别是从子进程的角度来看，
all the memory is marked as read only no rights.
所有的内存都被标记为只读，没有权限。
Right?
对吗？
Now when you read everything is perfect, right?
现在当你读到这一切都完美了，对吗？
Because you are going to read the same content,
因为你将要阅读相同的内容，
which is not modified as not modified as from the parrot.
这个句子的意思是"这个不是从鹦鹉那里修改过的"。
But now,
但是现在，
if the child wants to modify a piece of data,
如果孩子想要修改一段数据，
then because the pages are read only,
因此，由于这些页面是只读的，
then it's going to cause aa trap and exception is going to be intercepted
那么它将引发陷阱并拦截异常。
by the operating system.
由操作系统完成。
And the operating system now is going to copy the page.
操作系统现在要复制页面。
Read on the only page is going to create another copy now for the child.
现在，只读页面将为子进程创建另一个副本。
Now is going to give access to write to its own copy of that page to the child.
现在将允许子进程对自己的页面副本进行写操作。
When you exec,
当你执行exec时，
you only bring in parts of the binary inactive use,
你只需要引入二进制非活动使用的部分。
you just brings few pages in the memory or don't bring,
你只需要将几页内存加载进来或者不加载。
cause I am tired program into memory,
因为我已经很累了，需要将程序加载到内存中。
because that can be too big and sample some parts of the program you may know,
因为这可能会太大，并且只对程序的一部分进行抽样，你可能会了解到一些部分。
but never touch when you are running it.
但在运行时不要触摸它。
The similarly with a stack,
与栈类似，
you can extend the heap so forth.
你可以扩展堆空间等等。
This is another example about an animation about what happens
这是另一个关于发生了什么的动画的例子
when it's an end to an example and show you what happens.
当一个示例结束并展示发生了什么时。
When you start a new program,
当你启动一个新程序时，
you have a new program.
你有一个新的程序。
The program is on the disk.
程序在磁盘上。
It's not exact, is an extension.
这不是完全准确的，而是一个扩展。
You have the code,
你有代码。
you have some data, static data,
你有一些数据，静态数据，
and then for some other information,
然后关于其他信息，
you need to bring that in memory.
你需要将它加载到内存中。
You need to bring the code in memory in order to run.
你需要将代码加载到内存中才能运行。
And when you are going to start,
你什么时候开始？
you are going to bring some part of the code in memory.
你将要将代码的一部分加载到内存中。
And then you are going to bring some data in memory.
然后你将把一些数据加载到内存中。
And then you are going to allocate heap and the stack for that particular program.
然后你将为该特定程序分配堆和栈。
This is the view from the virtual address space.
这是虚拟地址空间的视图。
Bus stands for virtual address space of the process which was
Bus（总线）代表进程的虚拟地址空间，该地址空间是由操作系统分配给进程的。
instantiate to run the program.
实例化以运行程序。
And let's see.
让我们看看。
Then you obviously are going to back all these virtual addresses,
那么显然你将要备份所有这些虚拟地址，
everything in the virtual address,
虚拟地址中的所有内容
which is used by the program.
被程序使用的。
You are going to be backed to the disk.
你将被备份到磁盘上。
Finally, between the virtual address and the memory, you need to do,
最后，在虚拟地址和内存之间，你需要进行以下操作：
the translation is done with the page table.
翻译是通过页表完成的。
Some entry from the page table are going to.2 pages in the physical memory.
页表中的某些条目将占用物理内存中的2个页面。
And if a base table,
如果是一个基本表，
it's invalid,
这是无效的。
that doesn't exist in memory,
这在内存中不存在。
use a corresponding page table entry is going to point to the location
使用相应的页表项将指向该位置
of that page on the disk.
将该页面从磁盘中读取出来。
Fundamentally, what you need to do if that page is on the disk,
基本上，如果页面在磁盘上，你需要做的是：
is to have a function, something like that.
是要有一个函数，类似这样的东西。
It's a fine blog which takes an argument,
这是一篇很好的博客，它提出了一个论点。
the process id and the patient number of that.
进程ID和患者编号。
And and then for that paid number and the process,
然后对于那个已支付的号码和进程，
you are going to get a disk location of on the disk where you can find
你将获得一个磁盘位置，在该位置上可以找到...
that page.
那个页面。
So this is very similarly the paste table concept,
这与粘贴表格的概念非常相似，
but it is purely done purely in software.
但这完全是通过软件来实现的。
No, dld no, nothing like that.
不，没有，没有这样的事情。
Why do you take the pid why do you take the argument?
为什么要获取进程ID？为什么要获取参数？
Is the pid argument here?
这里有pid参数吗？
Anyone?
有人吗？
Because the virtual address space is per process.
因为虚拟地址空间是针对每个进程的。
The base tables are per process.
基本表是每个进程独立的。
If I give you only the page number is not well defined,
如果我只给你页码，这是不明确的。
because multiple processes,
因为有多个进程，
I can have a the same page numbers,
我可以有相同的页码。
right?
对的吗？
Because a patient number represents something in their virtual address space.
因为患者号码在他们的虚拟地址空间中代表着某个东西。
And each of them has a different virtual address space.
每个进程都有不同的虚拟地址空间。
So that's why you need to give the person the process identifier
这就是为什么你需要给这个人提供进程标识符的原因。
to identify the virtual address space.
识别虚拟地址空间。
Where do you store it?
你把它存放在哪里？
Obviously, you want to study the memory if you,
显然，如果你想要研究内存的话，
because if you store it on the disks and you need to bring it from the disk,
因为如果你将数据存储在磁盘上，而且需要从磁盘中读取数据，
is going to be one slower.
会慢一些。
That's pretty much it.
就是这样。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
By the way, like, in the case of the shared memory,
顺便提一下，在共享内存的情况下，
you also can share the disk between different applications processes.
你还可以在不同的应用程序进程之间共享磁盘。
So, for instance, and I like,
例如，我喜欢的是，
i'll show you next,
我会向你展示接下来的内容。
the way i'll show you that is like, for instance,
我将向您展示的方式是，例如，
here against his virtual address space for on process.
在这里，针对进程的虚拟地址空间进行操作。
And you can have another process and another process will have
而且你可以有另一个进程，而另一个进程将有
its own visual address space is owned by page labels.
它自己的可视地址空间由页面标签所拥有。
Here, it's about the stack and the heap and the data of the second process.
这里涉及到栈、堆和第二个进程的数据。
And assume that the second process is the first process.
假设第二个进程是第一个进程。
Running the same program are just two instances of the same program.
运行相同的程序只是同一个程序的两个实例。
In this particular case,
在这种特殊情况下，
as you can see,
正如你所看到的，
the code is shared,
代码是共享的，
because the code is read.
因为代码是可读的。
You remember, it's read only so it doesn't change.
你记得，它是只读的，所以不会改变。
So if you have to programs which uses out of instances,
如果你有两个程序使用了超出实例的资源，
sorry,
抱歉，有什么我可以帮助您的吗？
it's you have two instances of the same program
这意味着你有两个相同程序的实例。
than the virtual address space of the two,
比这两个的虚拟地址空间更大
the two instances,
这两个实例，
the two processes.
这两个进程。
They can share the same code on the disk.
它们可以在磁盘上共享相同的代码。
They said, share the same code, obviously,
他们说，共享相同的代码，显然，
and you can share also,
而且你也可以分享，
we can share the same old code also in the physical memory.
我们可以将相同的旧代码也存储在物理内存中。
Make sense?
有意义吗？
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Okay.
好的。
Again,
再次，
this page table,
这是一个页表。
the second process,
第二个进程，
some of the pages have been memory, some of them,
一些页面已经被存入内存，其中一些页面，
the one which are not in memories are backed on this.
不在内存中的数据会被备份到这里。
Now say the process active,
现在说一下进程是活动的。
the first process is active.
第一个进程处于活动状态。
Then if you are going to have fetched an instruction on access
那么，如果你要在访问时获取一条指令
and physical memory,
和物理内存，
then you look in the base table.
然后你查看基本表。
If, say the base table entry is invalid,
假设基表项无效，
then you have a page fold as the operating system locates a block
当操作系统定位到一个块时，会发生页面折叠。
on the disk which contains a page,
在包含页面的磁盘上，
and then move it to the memory.
然后将其移动到内存中。
Is another summary step by step of handling a baseball.
处理棒球的另一个逐步摘要。
Again, you access a memory,
再次，你访问了一个内存位置，
mutual memory, physically,
共享内存，物理上，
the and it's step one.
这是第一步。
Say, the program, the associated page table entries invalid,
程序中的相关页表项无效，
these results in a trap baseball with the operating system,
这些结果导致操作系统陷入了一个陷阱。
locate the block where the page is stored on the disk,
定位页面在磁盘上存储的块。
bring the page in memory,
将页面加载到内存中，
in a free frame,
在一个空闲帧中，
page frame updates,
页面帧更新
a page table entries,
页表项
and restart the instruction.
并重新启动指令。
A few announcements the hallmark for has been released.
已发布了一些重要公告。
This week.
本周。
Please understand the design reviews.
请理解设计评审。
Remember, the design review starts at the hour.
请记住，设计审查将在整点开始。
They are not on the berkeley time.
他们不按照伯克利时间。
Please.
请。
So you give time to everyone.
所以你给每个人时间。
They can get the feedback from the ta in mind that you need to participate
你需要参与并牢记TA的反馈意见。
during design reviews.
在设计审查期间。
A part of your grade is based on that.
你的成绩的一部分是基于这个的。
And other than that,
除此之外，
I know that there are now many deadlines.
我知道现在有很多截止日期。
There are no deadlines for the next 2 weeks,
接下来的两周内没有任何截止日期。
but the next following weeks of november 1st will be pretty brutal.
但是11月1日之后的接下来几周将会非常艰难。
So as such,
因此，
please make progress on homework for a project to and start studying
请在项目的作业上取得进展并开始学习。
about meter to,
关于"meter to"的问题，可以理解为将单位从米转换为其他单位的问题。
which is mostly the materials we are learning.
我们主要学习的材料是什么？
We have been learned since the first meter.
我们从第一米开始学习。
So meter two will still have some of,
所以仪表二仍然会有一些
like, maybe 10,
大概10个左右
20% from the materials of mid term one.
期中考试一的材料占总分的20%。
But this means that 1890% of the materials will be from the lectures
但这意味着有1890%的材料将来自讲座内容。
since midterm one.
自期中考以来。
Now let's switch the gears and answer the following key question.
现在让我们转换一下思路，回答以下关键问题。
During a page fault,
在页面错误期间，
you need to bring a page from the disk to the memory.
你需要将磁盘上的一个页面调入内存。
How do you find room for that page?
你如何找到那个页面的空间？
If there is no room like we discussed,
如果没有像我们讨论过的那样的空间，
we are going to find a page before it's dirty,
我们要在页面变脏之前找到它。
save it on the disk and replace it with a new page.
将其保存在磁盘上，并用新页面替换它。
But typically this is quite expensive.
但通常来说这是相当昂贵的。
Writing page bring up beijing is very expensive.
写作页面提到北京非常昂贵。
What many operating systems do in the background?
操作系统在后台做了很多工作。
They kick off some of the right back,
他们将一些右后卫踢出场
some of the dirty pages to the disk.
将一些脏页写回磁盘。
If you need to replace one,
如果你需要更换一个，
then you don't need to write it back.
那么你不需要回复了。
This is kind of periodically,
这是一种周期性的行为。
it's a cleaning process to reduce the overhead of the demand paging.
这是一种清理过程，旨在减少需求分页的开销。
Now, but even if you have this background mechanism,
现在，即使你有这个背景机制，
you still need to answer the following question,
你仍然需要回答以下问题：
which pages are you going to write to the disk?
你打算将哪些页面写入磁盘？
For each pages?
每个页面？
You are going to evict to bring a new beijing.
你将要驱逐以引进一个新的北京。
And the way we you think about that by now,
到目前为止，我们对此的看法是这样的，
when you talk about scheduling and so forth,
当谈到调度等问题时，
you need to come up with a policy.
你需要制定一项政策。
When you come up with a policy to dictate which guides which pages
当你制定一项政策来决定哪个指导哪个页面时
are written back or are evicted from the main moment memory.
被写回或从主内存中驱逐。
There are certain properties you need you think about about utilization.
在考虑利用率时，有一些特定的属性需要您思考。
You want to have high utilization of the memory.
你希望内存的利用率高。
That's because it's a scarce resource.
这是因为它是一种稀缺资源。
You may want fairness between different processes or immune to enforce priority.
您可能希望在不同进程之间实现公平性或强制优先级。
So that's kind of you keep in mind that we are not going to implement
非常感谢您的关注，请记住我们不打算实现这个功能。
different policies here.
这里有不同的政策。
But this is for you to keep in mind that is a typical questions you
但是请你记住，这是一个典型的问题。
are going to be faced with when you are going to design a base replacement
当你设计一个基础替换时，你将面临以下问题：
policy.
政策。
So is a key model.
所以是一个关键模型。
You have in mind when you run a program,
当你运行一个程序时，你会有什么想法。
11of these models,
其中的11个模型，
it's about the working set.
这是关于工作集的内容。
So that what is a a working set, roughly speaking,
工作集（Working Set）大致来说是指在一段时间内，进程或程序所使用的内存页面的集合。
is the set of addresses whose content,
是指内容的地址集合，
if you have in the physical memory,
如果你在物理内存中有的话，
then the programs works well.
那么程序运行正常。
There are very few baseballs.
棒球很少。
If any,
如果有的话，
right?
是的，没错。
And this tried to show a depiction of a this is for a program.
这是一个试图展示一个程序的描述。
On the x axis, you have the time.
在x轴上，你有时间。
And on the y axis, you have the address.
在y轴上，你有地址。
And each rectangle is the height of the rectangle represent.
每个矩形的高度表示该矩形的高度。
What addresses are accessed at a given time by the program.
程序在给定时间访问了哪些地址。
And the length represent for how long you access content from these addresses.
长度表示您从这些地址访问内容的持续时间。
Right?
对吗？
So this is,
所以这是，
and as you can see here,
正如你在这里所看到的，
this is execution.
这是执行。
The thread.
线程。
Stuff is execution of the program.
"Stuff" 是程序的执行。
And at different times,
而在不同的时间，
you have different working sets.
你们有不同的工作集。
So working set here is that if you,
所以这里的工作集是指如果你，
if you draw a vertical line at a given time,
如果你在给定的时间画一条垂直线，
then everything,
那么一切，
all the blue rectangle it enters this line,
所有蓝色矩形都进入这条线。
intersects represent the working set,
交集表示工作集合。
represent the addresses whose content should be in the physical memory,
表示应该在物理内存中存储内容的地址
so that we do not have page faults.
这样我们就不会发生页面错误。
And the working set.
工作集。
One property, in general,
一般来说，有一个属性，
is that is much smaller than the entire address space of the program,
这比程序的整个地址空间要小得多。
and also is changing over time.
而且它也在随着时间的推移而改变。
Obviously, if you can keep all the working set in memory or in the cache,
显然，如果你能将所有的工作集保留在内存或缓存中，
then is great.
那太好了。
The heat rate will be one.
热速率将为1。
If you cannot, then the hit rate will not be on.
如果你不能做到，那么命中率就无法实现。
And you are going to have also some mistake.
而且你也会犯一些错误。
This also shows the cache size,
这也显示了缓存的大小，
how much of the program is stored in the cash for this previous example.
在这个先前的例子中，程序的多少存储在缓存中？
And you start with very little,
而你从一无所有开始，
and you have here a lot of come,
而且你在这里有很多选择。
and the hit rate is also very low.
而且命中率也非常低。
Sorry,
抱歉，
let me back that here.
让我在这里备份一下。
When the x axis here is a cache size,
这里的x轴表示缓存大小，
you are looking here at caches of different sites.
你正在查看不同网站的缓存。
On the y axis,
在y轴上，
you have the hit rate.
你有命中率。
If the cache says is infinite,
如果缓存大小为无限大，
the heat rate will be one.
热速率将为1。
So when the cast size,
当角色的规模增加时，
or in other words,
换句话说，
on the cast size is larger than the working set,
当缓存大小大于工作集时，
what is the working set is in the cash?
在计算机缓存中，工作集是指当前正在被活跃使用的数据和指令的集合。它代表了程序在特定时间段内访问的内存块。工作集通常是根据最近使用的原则来确定，即最近被访问的数据和指令很可能在不久的将来再次被访问。通过将工作集保留在缓存中，可以提高程序的性能，减少对主存的访问次数。
Then the hit ladies.
然后是击中女士们。
And then, as if the cast,
然后，仿佛是演员一样，
I say it's very small,
我觉得它很小。
then the heat rate will be very little,
那么热量传递速率将非常小。
because probably all the working set will be doesn't fit in the cash.
因为很可能整个工作集都无法放入缓存中。
Right?
对吗？
Any fetch of an instruction,
任何指令的取指操作，
every access of the data will result on.
每次对数据的访问都会产生结果。
It is going to result in a miss.
这将导致未命中。
Right?
对吗？
Any questions here?
有什么问题吗？
So if the cash it's a shared between different processes,
那么如果现金是在不同进程之间共享的，
like, is a second level cash,
就像是一个二级缓存，
then you need to feed multiple working set in the same cache.
那么你需要在同一个缓存中存储多个工作集。
And actually, this figure shows,
实际上，这个图表展示了，
when you have multiple working sets in the same cache,
当在同一个缓存中有多个工作集时，
each of these inflection points is when a new working set is
每个拐点都代表一个新的工作集。
fitting in the cache,
适应缓存
obviously are going to have a very similar behavior for demand painting.
显然，对于需求绘制，它们的行为将非常相似。
Again, demand painting is as cash.
再次强调，需求画作是现金。
Now, when we are talking about the working set,
现在，当我们谈论工作集时，
we have this kind of nice model, like I mentioned,
我们有这种很好的模型，就像我之前提到的那样。
that actually the program is spending most of the time or all the time,
实际上，该程序大部分或全部时间都在运行。
a in a relatively small region of the other space.
在另一个空间的相对较小区域中的a。
And this makes the cash very effective.
这使得现金非常有效。
However, there are other models for locality like ziff and distribution.
然而，还有其他关于局部性的模型，例如ziff和分布模型。
In this case,
在这种情况下，
you do have this is, for instance,
你确实有这个，例如，
on this figure, what you see.
在这个图上，你看到了什么。
Here it's a rank.
这是一个排名。
This represent, say,
这表示，比如说，
think about each of this is a page.
将每个页面都视为一个单独的页面。
There are pages are ranking the decreasing order of their popularity
有页面按照它们的受欢迎程度降序排名。
about how often they are accessed.
关于它们被访问的频率。
The popularity of access is on the y axis.
访问的流行度在y轴上。
They say that the first page is accessed20% of the time.
据说第一页被访问的频率为20%。
You access a memory,
你访问了一个内存。
access the first page.
访问第一页。
This is what it says.
这是它的内容。
Right?
对吗？
Now,
现在，
the problem with this distribution and this popularity is shown
这种分发和流行度的问题被展示出来了。
by the blue line.
沿着蓝线走。
The problem with this one is that with this distribution is
这个问题在于这个分布是这样的
a very challenging distribution,
一个非常具有挑战性的分布。
is that it also has a long tail,
它也有一条长尾巴。
mostly axis.
主要是轴。
Most of the axis are on a very few pages.
大多数轴都在很少的页面上。
But there is some a lot a huge amount of pages are accessed infrequent.
但是有一些页面很少被访问。
And this creates problems,
这会引发问题，
because no matter,
因为无论如何，
even if you have a big cash,
即使你有很多现金，
we are still going to have misses because of these very rare items.
由于这些非常罕见的物品，我们仍然会出现遗漏情况。
But what this shows you is that even if you have a small cash,
但这表明即使你只有一点点现金，
you get quite a bit of value because a few pages are responsible for most taxes.
你可以获得相当大的价值，因为只有少数几页负责大部分税收。
The second thing is that if you have a very large cash,
第二件事是，如果你有很多现金，
it's a diminishing return.
这是递减收益。
It may not benefit a lot.
可能没有太多好处。
You still have substantial misses.
你仍然有很多错误。
Questions?
有问题吗？
I don't know that video,
我不知道那个视频。
but there are many situations in which you are going.
但是有很多情况下你会去。
This distribution is very common.
这个分布非常常见。
One, it's our web pages.
一、这是我们的网页。
I'm talking about web pages, right?
我在谈论网页，对吗？
When you access the web pages,
当你访问网页时，
they have as if we are distribution.
他们好像把我们当作分发机构。
And is very common,
这是非常常见的，
is a population of cities.
是一个城市的人口。
There are a few cities with very large population and a few of them.
有几个人口非常庞大的城市，其中有一些。
But there are many of them with a smaller population.
但是有许多国家的人口较少。
It's a very common distribution model.
这是一个非常常见的分发模型。
Again, what we care about is estimated access time.
我们关心的是估计的访问时间。
And the estimated access time is a hit rate times hit time.
估计的访问时间是命中率乘以命中时间。
It's a latency to access the data in memory,
访问内存中的数据会产生延迟。
plus miss rate plus the miss time.
加上缺失率再加上缺失时间。
And the miss time is the time it takes to bring the data in memory
而"miss time"是将数据加载到内存中所需的时间。
from the disk if it's not there.
如果磁盘上没有找到，就从磁盘中获取。
And it's not there, because they missed the heat rate plaza,
这是因为他们错过了热量率广场，所以它不在那里。
miss rate is one.
缺失率为1。
You can also rewrite the equation by having this penalty,
你也可以通过引入这个惩罚项来重新改写方程。
by denoting, miss time,
通过表示，错过时间
my minus hit time.
我的减法击中时间。
This is the overhead where to miss.
这是错过的开销。
This is miss penalty.
这是缺失惩罚。
You can realize the equation at hit time plus miss rate times miss penalty.
你可以通过命中时间加上失误率乘以失误惩罚来实现这个方程。
Here is a very simple example.
这是一个非常简单的例子。
Memory access time is 200 nanoseconds average page for service time.
内存访问时间为平均200纳秒每页的服务时间。
So bringing the page from the disk into memory.
将页面从磁盘加载到内存中。
It's 8 million seconds.
这是800万秒。
Let's say p is the probability of miss one minus ps and the probability of hit.
假设 p 是未命中的概率，即 1 减去 p_s 和命中的概率。
This means that we are using the same the second equation.
这意味着我们正在使用相同的第二个方程。
The access time is made like this time is 200 and seconds
访问时间是以此方式表示的，时间为200秒。
plus p times 8 million nanoseconds.
加上 p 乘以 800 万纳秒。
If just one out of 1,000 pages,
如果只有1,000页中的一张，
page axis is a fault,
页轴错误。
this is 0.1%.
这是0.1%。
The access time is of over eight micro seconds or 40 times
访问时间超过八微秒，或者是40倍的时间。
more than just accessing the memory.
不仅仅是访问内存。
So the slowdown is huge.
所以这个减速非常严重。
If you want to slow to have a slowdown only by ten per or to 10% slow down,
如果你想要减速只有百分之十或者减速百分之十
then you can physics in the equation.
然后你可以在方程中加入物理学。
And the p is a probability of miss should be lower
而且p是错过的概率应该更低。
than 1 page in 400,000 axis.
超过400,000个轴的一页以上。
That gives you a sense about how important is
这让你对重要性有了一定的了解
a patient replacement policies in minimizing the miss,
最小化错过的病人替换策略
right?
对的？
And that's how you use.
这就是你如何使用的方法。
This is right here.
就在这里。
It's an example of why here was a demand.
这是一个说明为什么存在需求的例子。
Beijing is fully associative,
北京是完全关联的。
right?
对的？
Because you just want to avoid any misses are at any cost.
因为你只想以任何代价避免任何错误。
Or it's a question here.
或者这里是一个问题。
What is the intuition behind why the hit rate is higher for the lower ranks?
为什么较低级别的命中率较高的直观理解是什么？
It's all here, right?
都在这里了，对吗？
Let me see.
让我看看。
Actually, a it's a rank of popularity.
实际上，这是一个受欢迎程度的排名。
Right?
对吗？
So actually,
实际上，
these pages are ordered in the decreasing order of their popularity.
这些页面按照受欢迎程度递减的顺序排列。
So that I get to go is a popularity.
所以我能去是一种受欢迎的事情。
So there is nothing subtle here.
这里没有什么微妙的地方。
Okay?
好的？
That doesn't mean anything else and being pop a major of popularity.
这并不意味着其他任何事情，也不代表流行度的主要因素。
Okay, again,
好的，再来一次，
see you remember about catching,
记得关于捕获的事情。
what are the type of misses,
缺失的类型有哪些？
compulsory misses,
强制性缺失
pages that have never been paid into memory?
从未被加载到内存中的页面
This is when you start a program,
这是当你启动一个程序时，
you need to read the code, right?
你需要阅读代码，对吗？
For instance,
例如，
capacity misses.
容量不足。
You don't have enough memory.
你的内存不足。
What do you doing this?
你在做什么？
In this case?
在这种情况下？
Obviously, you can increase a number,
显然，你可以增加一个数字。
increase the memory size.
增加内存大小。
Or if you can share the memory between processes and
或者如果你可以在进程之间共享内存，那么
give each process certain amount of memory.
为每个进程分配一定量的内存。
Or in some cases,
在某些情况下，
as you'll see,
正如你所看到的，
one solution is to kill one of the processes.
一个解决方案是终止其中一个进程。
The remaining processes,
剩下的进程，
they have enough physical memory conflict misses.
他们有足够的物理内存冲突缺失。
You don't have those slides, technically,
从技术上讲，你没有那些幻灯片。
because a it's a fully associative cash,
因为它是一个完全关联的高速缓存。
right?
对的？
And policy misses,
以及政策失误，
it's about depends on the replacement policy we are going to use.
这取决于我们将要使用的替换策略。
Here we just want a better replacement policy to minimize the misses.
在这里，我们只是希望有一个更好的替换策略来最小化缺失。
Okay?
好的？
So pay deployment policies.
支付部署政策。
It's again,
又是这样，
those you learn a few of them last time.
上次你学了其中的一些知识。
The same similar are here,
这里有相同的相似之处。
54.
First in, first out,
先进先出 (FIFO)
you throw out the oldest page or a big the oldest page is some degree
你可以选择丢弃最旧的页面，或者丢弃一个较大的最旧页面。
of fairness in terms of the access.
公平性在访问方面的意义。
But it can be also bad.
但它也可能是坏的。
Why when it's five or bad is when you have a very popular page which is
为什么当你的页面非常受欢迎时，它会变得糟糕或不可用？
access over and over.
反复访问
Right?
对吗？
This is also one of the pages which are going to be the oldest in the
这也是将成为最古老的页面之一之一
could be the oldest on the program started.
可能是该项目中最古老的开始。
It loaded this page,
它加载了这个页面。
like, for instance,
例如，比如说，
the code like for these powerpoint slides,
这些幻灯片上的代码类似于以下内容：
the code which go is responsible for going from one slide and displaying
go函数的作用是从一个幻灯片跳转到另一个幻灯片并显示。
the next slide.
下一张幻灯片。
This is,
这是，
I am a using that code from the beginning of the lecture.
我从讲座开始就在使用那段代码。
That was one of the first pieces of code which was loaded in memory.
这是最早加载到内存中的代码之一。
But if I use 54,
但是如果我使用54，
that will be also a piece of code should be evicted.
这也是应该被删除的一段代码。
And if you evicted,
如果你被驱逐了，
it just to be loaded again next time, I went on,
下次只需重新加载，我继续进行。
i'm turning to the next slide at random is very simple.
随机跳转到下一张幻灯片非常简单。
So they are very fast to implement also in hardware.
因此，它们在硬件上实现起来非常快速。
Typically, you have this is still be when you need to be super fast.
通常情况下，当你需要非常快速时，你会这样做。
Or the downside is random,
或者说缺点是随机的，
it's not predictable.
它是不可预测的。
It's minimum.
这是最小的。
And the minimum.
最小值。
It's the optimal one.
这是最优的选择。
Right?
对吗？
What is the optimal replacement policy?
什么是最优的替换策略？
Right?
对吗？
You should know that from cash,
你应该知道，从现金支付，
what is the optimal replacement policy?
什么是最优的替换策略？
You want to replace the page,
你想要替换页面。
which won't be used for the longest time.
哪个将不会被使用最长时间。
It's as simple as that.
就是这么简单。
The problem with this is that you need to predict the future and you don't know.
这个问题在于你需要预测未来，而你并不知道未来会发生什么。
And the way around it is to use the past as a good predictor of the future.
解决这个问题的方法是利用过去作为预测未来的良好指标。
That is, if a page has not been used for a while,
也就是说，如果一个页面在一段时间内没有被使用，
then the page will not assume that the page will not be, again,
那么页面将不会假设页面不会再次出现。
access for a while.
暂时访问权限。
If the page was just used before recently,
如果页面最近刚被使用过，
it's going to be likely used again in the future.
它很可能在将来再次被使用。
Any questions here?
这里有什么问题吗？
This is approximation is the least recently used.
这个近似值是最近最少使用的。
Right?
对吗？
Just replays a page that hasn't been used for the longest time.
只需重新加载最长时间未使用的页面即可。
If the programs have every locality,
如果程序具有良好的局部性，
this is a pretty good policy.
这是一个非常好的政策。
How we implement it.
我们如何实现它。
One,
一,
you can simply implement it.
你可以简单地实现它。
You can keep a list of pages.
你可以维护一个页面列表。
And you a when you access a page,
当你访问一个页面时，
you put it as a head of you move it to the head of the queue.
你将它放在队列头部，然后将其移动到队列的头部。
And the pages as the last in this,
并且将这些页面放在最后。
least, is a page which hasn't been accessed for the longest time.
最少访问的页面是指最长时间没有被访问的页面。
Okay.
好的。
It's a great question.
这是一个很好的问题。
Is there anything you can do when you are writing code to help decrease
在编写代码时，有什么方法可以帮助减少？
page misses?
页面缺失？
This is a great question.
这是一个很好的问题。
Yes, you can do it.
是的，你可以做到。
I'll give you one example,
我给你举一个例子，
like, for instance,
例如，比如说，
and this is used and known by people do high performance computing.
这被人们用于高性能计算，并且被广泛认知。
Say, you have a matrix and say,
假设你有一个矩阵，假设
you want to multiply the matrix or do some operation on the matrix.
你想要对矩阵进行乘法运算或者进行一些矩阵操作。
You can iterate on browse,
你可以在浏览器上进行迭代。
or you to iterate on columns.
让你迭代列。
Now is very important about how this matrix is stored in memory.
现在非常重要的是如何将这个矩阵存储在内存中。
Typically start row by row.
通常按行开始。
You start first row,
你从第一行开始。
then the next row and the next row.
然后是下一行和下一行。
If the matrix is large,
如果矩阵很大，
right?
对的？
If I want to greet, say,
如果我想打招呼，比如说，
to all the elements of the matrix,
对于矩阵的所有元素，
if I can, i'm going to italy by row is going to have a good cash locality.
如果我能的话，我打算坐船去意大利，那里有很好的现金交易地点。
Because I start to with the first row matrix,
因为我从第一行矩阵开始。
i'm already going to start to bring.
我已经准备开始了。
The first page contains a lot of elements from the first row.
第一页包含了许多来自第一行的元素。
So they are going to be all already in the cache when I am going to access them.
当我要访问它们时，它们将全部已经在缓存中。
Now say, I am going to write the same program,
现在假设我要编写相同的程序，
but i'm going to access columns.
但是我要访问列。
I am going to access the first element.
我要访问第一个元素。
I'm going to bring a page.
我要带来一页。
Now, the next element i'm going to access is going to be from the next row,
现在，我将要访问的下一个元素将来自下一行。
not in the same row.
不在同一行。
The next row that can result in another miss.
And I need to bring another page just to access only one element
from that page and so forth.
By the time I go back to access the second element from the first row,
that page may be already gone,
right?
Because may not all the pages may fit in cash.
So that's what you can do.
Like that's an example you want.
Or the dldr here,
you want to write your program to preserve locality,
another things which kind of destroy locality.
If you have goals, if you write a program,
he jumps around to go to.
That destroys a code locality.
I know that a large number of random access is on the hip is
generally bad for cash hit rates.
That's the same generally applies to minimize page misses.
I again,
it's like random.
It's not going, you will use random because it's fast.
But in this particular case,
because it's so costly to the baseball is so costly,
you really want to avoid random.
We still plb use random because you want to be extremely fast, right?
That happens actually in hardware.
Hopefully, I I answered this question if I didn't answer,
ask it again.
And maybe rephrase, what do you think?
I I I may have missed from your question.
Wouldn't this mean?
We have to take a software fault on every axis?
This, I think,
is refers to the examples I gave you about matrices going by columns.
In the worst case,
this means that you can take us a baseball on every access to a record.
No, is allah.
You're not.
It's again, it's like,
if you have something which is used very often,
then every time when you access it,
you are going to, again,
when you put here in this example.
Sorry.
When you put here in this example,
is, again, if I access space seven,
I am going to put it as ahead of the queue or the head of the list.
Accessing page on.
I'm going to put it ahead of the list, assessing page two.
Now the pastry is going to head off the list.
If I access something very often,
then they are going to be close to the head of the list.
So they are not going to be removed.
They are not going to be available.
Question,
does that mean that we have to work all pts and scan the valley beats?
Every so often begins the list?
That's a great.
Access fits, use, beats, they use, beats.
You refer, you are referring to the use beats.
That's a good point.
You could do that.
As we are going to see.
Next,
this is a precise implementation of the list,
at least recently used,
but it's expensive to implement what we are going to implement.
It's an approximation of allergy,
right?
That's what you are going to implement.
But before it goes there,
and we are going to show how we are going to implement an approximation of allergy.
Again,
we want to implement and as approximation ideal because we
don't want to manipulate point that is to do many memory access is
whenever we access a page before that,
let's look at a few other replacement policies.
This is 54.
And here we have a cash,
or which has three slots,
or you have three frames.
And this is your order in which we access the sequence.
We access these pages.
As the pages are denoted abc ds,
there are 4 pages.
I'm going to first access a's and b's,
and c and so forth.
Let's access a initially,
the cache or memory is empty.
We are going to save use the first page frame
to start a then b still have you available slot available frames?
I'm going to use the second one and to use and then use the server.
Now, things become interesting here.
Now I am going to come to access a again and a it's already in,
so it's fine.
I'm happy.
I'm not going to do anything.
I'm going to access it.
It's already in memory.
B is the same.
But now is b d is not in the memory.
What do I need to do?
And the memory is full.
So I need to make room for it.
Each page i'm going to evict here is in first out.
So i'm going to evict the page,
which was the first,
the first, which was brought in the memory,
right?
Which is a I'm going to replace cpcd now,
after d it's a well,
now a is against this.
The memory is full.
So I need to pick a page to ab and I'm going to pick which on b now,
the next one is the, again,
it's in memory, not only to do anything.
Then b now I don't have b in memory.
I have only ac and d right?
I need to replace one,
which one was the oldest?
We see,
I am.
And then ci am going to replace d with.
And then finally,
BB is already here.
How many page folds I had?
1234.
These are capacities.
And in addition to that,
I have three, other.
Mrs.
And these are what kind of misses are those compulsory misses?
So I have three compulsory misses.
Four capacity misses,
seven faults,
seven misses.
And here just noticed that this was a bad decision to replace a when we
brought the d in,
because the next axis was there.
So let's keep this in mind.
And with that,
i'll stop here.
We are going to continue to discuss about the patriots placement policies
next lecture.
Thank you.